

linkedin.com/in/ben-liu github.com/ben196888 (+61) 413 188 912 ben196888@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Ben Liu is focusing on web apps developing these 5 years. He worked in JavaScript with ReactJS for 3.5 years and NodeJS for 2 years. He is always passionate about new technology and likes to learn new ideas from developer events and open source projects. He is not only an avid problem solver but also a good autodidact who is keen on more than one solution.

SKILLS

Skills JavaScript, TypeScript, Docker, Golang, Python

Libraries ReactJS, Redux, RxJS, NodeJS, Angular, EmberJS, Restify, Serverless

Databases Mongo, Redis, Firebase, PostgreSQL

Tools Jenkins, Buildkite, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch

WORK EXPERIENCE

Predictive Hire, Melbourne, Australia

Oct. 2018-Jun. 2019

Software Engineer

- Designed and built a chatbot website to inspire 1 investor and 10 potential customers.
- Led 2 Devs to integrate applicant tracking system to extend 33% of enterprise customers.
- Reduced 600% CI/CD run time by decoupling micro-services in same integration test rate.
- Created a process and guided 1 Scientist to deliver NLP models for enterprise customers.
- Led 1 Scientist and 1 Intern to transit proof-of-concept scripts to the product code base.

Tabcorp, Melbourne, Australia

Developer

Jan. 2017-Sep. 2018

- Led 3 Devs and 1 DevOps to build an API service for 5000 transactions per min in 4 weeks.
- Solved 3rd party API issues across the Ops team and Devs team on production in one day.
- Reduced DOM unit tests 3500% execution time by replacing headless chrome with JSDOM.
- Increased unit tests coverage rate from 75% to higher than 95% by adding 100+ test cases.
- \bullet Resolved the browser crashed issue by throttling when receiving 150+/s data stream.
- Unblocked bottleneck to render 500% more transactions per second by queueing the stream.

HopebayTech, Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2014-Oct. 2016

Software Engineer

- Developed 100+ users internal web services, integrated G Suite and Slack.
- Created CI pipelines for 5 projects, integrated Jenkins, Gitlab, and Slack.
- Dockerized 5 web services, 3 databases, and 2 cross-compiling build system in 3 projects.
- Centralized system monitoring platform for 200-unit servers, integrated Elasticsearch.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Mathematics

2009-2014